Serge Diaghilev/Serge Lifar Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- I. Printed Music Material, 1750-1950 (Box 1-67)
  - A. General (Box 1-65)
    - Berners, Lord
      - Le carrosse du Saint-Sacrement. London: J. & W. Chester, 1923., Piano-vocal score; 158 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.9723.; Language note: French (Box-folder 5/2)
      - Le carrosse du Saint-Sacrement. London: J. & W. Chester, 1923., Piano-vocal score; 159 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.9723.; Unbound, labeled "2nd proof" on title page; contains numerous annotations and proofreader's markings, in ink.; Language note: French (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Berzhe, R.
      - Vdali ot Rodiny See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68.]
      - Vinovaty rozy See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
      - Vliublennaia See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68.]
    - Bessmertnyĭ, Mikhaĭl
      - Tsyganka Masha, op. 14. Leningrad: Ars, n.d., Voice and piano; score ;3 p.; Plate no. L.W.386.; Language note: Russian; Composer also known by the name: Bezsmertnyĭ, Mikhaĭl (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Binet, Jean
      - Le Printemps. [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Photoreproduced orchestral score; 113 p. (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Bizet, Georges
      - L'Arlésienne. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Reduction for solo piano; score; 77 p.; Plate no. A.C.2484-7015, .3273, .2484.; Language note: French; Solo piano reduction containing vocal selections, dialogue indications (Box-folder 6/2)
      - Chants du Rhin. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Solo piano; score; 37 p.; Plate no. H.4521.(1), .4522.(2), .4523.(3), .4524.(4), .4525.(5), .4526.(6). (Box-folder 6/3)
      - Chasse fantastique. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Solo piano; score; 14 p.; Plate no. H.4507. (Box-folder 6/4)
      - Djamileh, op. 24. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 129 p.; Plate no. A.C.2380.; Language note: French (Box-folder 6/5)
      - Djamileh, op. 24. Milan: E. Sonzogno, 1892., Piano-vocal score; 143 p.; Plate no. A.C.8694.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 6/6)
      - Don Procopio. Paris: A. Choudens, 1905., Piano-vocal score; 273 p.; Plate no. A.C.13062.; Language note: French; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 7/1)
      - Jeux d'enfants, op. 22. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Piano, four hands; score; 63 p.; Plate no. nos. D. & F.1365.(1) through (12). (Box-folder 7/2)
      - La jolie fille de Perth. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 260 p.; Plate no. A.C.1523.; Language note: French (Box-folder 7/3)
      - La jolie fille de Perth: [Excerpts ("Les bohémiennes").] Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 16 p.; Plate no. A.C.2795. (Box-folder 7/4)
      - Roma: Suite de concert, no. 3. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Reduction for solo piano; score; 59 p.; Plate no. A.C.4851. (Box-folder 7/5)
      - Variations chromatiques. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Solo piano; score; 15 p.; Plate no. A.C.4659. (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Boccherini, Luigi
      - Minuetto, A major. [Quintetto, strings, op. 6, no. 2: Minuetto.] Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged by M. Saladino for solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 45917. (Box-folder 7/7)
      - Minuetto, G major. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., String quintet; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 54544. (Box-folder 7/8)
      - Quartetti, op. 6, nos. 1-3. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1915., String quartet; score; 53 p.; Plate no. 115370. (Box-folder 7/9)
      - Quartetti, op. 6, nos. 4-6. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1915., String quartet; score; 53 p.; Plate no. 115371. (Box-folder 7/10)
      - Quintetto, op. 2, no. 6: Minuetto, A major. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., String quintet; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 113074. (Box-folder 7/11)
      - Siciliana, C minor. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., String sextet; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 113076. (Box-folder 7/12)
      - Sonate, no. 3, G major: Largo, Minuet. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Cello and piano; cello part, piano score; 1 p.; 3 p.; Also published Paris: B. Roudanez, n.d.; Plate no. S.R. et Cie.79. (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Boieldieu, François Adrien
      - Le calife de Bagdad. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 97 p.; Plate no. H.3289, H.3295.; Language note: French (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Bonaterra, Luís
      - La festa de la rambla. [=La fête de la promenade.] Paris: Éditions espagnoles J. Garzón, n.d., Parts for: voice, vn I, vc-cb, sax I (alto)-sax II (tenor), sax III (alto), tpt-tbn, perc (1 p. each).; Plate no. 1778.; On verso of each part: corresponding instrumental part for Mostazo [-Morales], Juan, Coplas; all Mostazo material is included with the Bonaterra material.; Containing chordal indications for accordion; Language note: French (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Borisov, B. S.
      - IA pomniu den'. Moscow: A. Gun, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. A.19.G.; Language note: Russian; publicity material on back cover dated 1915 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Borodin, Aleksandr Porfir'evich
      - Kniaz' Igor'. [=Prince Igor.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1889., Piano-vocal score; 371 p.; Plate no. 120.119-143, 119 [120]-153, 119-154, 119, 119-155 through 119-170.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil.; Language note: Russian; Language note: French; Language note: German (Box-folder 8/4)
      - Kniaz' Igor': Ariia Kniazia Igoria. [=Prince Igor: Prince Igor's aria.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, n.d., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 119-161.; Language note: Russian; Language note: French; Language note: German (Box-folder 8/5)
      - Kniaz' Igor'. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1888., Parts for chorus: altos [2] p.; tenors [18] p.; basses [?] p.; Plate no. 117.; Italian text inscribed in sections of tenor part, in red ink.; Complete in 41 p.: altos [incomplete: cover page, p. 1-2 only]; tenors [incomplete: p. 23 through 41 (end of opera) only]; basses; Language note: Italian; Language note: Russian; Language note: French (Box-folder 8/6)
      - More. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 13 p.; Plate no. 28394.; Language note: Russian; Language note: French (Box-folder 8/7)
      - Petite suite; Scherzo. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 27 p.; Plate no. A.L.8686.; Contains annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 8/8)
      - Petite suite. London: Augener, 1914., Solo piano; score; 23 p.; Plate no. 14676. (Box-folder 8/9)
      - Petite suite: Au couvent. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. A.L.8686. (Box-folder 8/10)
      - Serenata alla spagnola. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1888., Arranged by T. Jadoul for solo piano; score; 14 p.; Plate no. 2340. (Box-folder 8/11)
      - Symphonie no. 1, E-flat major. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Piano, four hands; score; 75 p.; Plate no. A.L.8687. (Box-folder 8/12)
      - Symphonie no. 2, B minor. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Piano, four hands; score; 63 p.; Plate no. A.L.8688. (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Bortkevich, Sergeĭ Eduardovich
      - Tausend und eine Nacht, op. 37. Leipzig: D. Rahter, 1928., Solo piano; score; 35 p.; Plate no. 4447.; Composer also known by the name: Bortkiewicz, Serge (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Bosk, A.
      - Piesnaia skazka. Moscow: C.IA. IAmbor', n.d., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 199.; Composer also known by the name: Bosc, Auguste (Box-folder 9/2)
      - Rose-Mousse See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68
    - Boyce, William
      - Three pieces. London: Novello, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 5 p.; 12 p.; Plate no. 12765. (Box-folder 9/3)
      - The Chaplet See: I.B. Collections, Box 1 (S/62), p. 67
      - Lyra Brittanica See: I.B. Collections, Box 1 (S/62), p. 67
      - Solomon See: I.B. Collections, Box 1 (S/62), p. 67
    - Braga, Gaetano
      - La serenata. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Arranged by J. Rummel for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. D. & F.2368. (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Brahms, Johannes
      - Danses hongroises: 5. Allegro. Paris: J. Hamelle, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. J.6699. (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Bretón, Tomás
      - Escenas andaluzas: 2. Polo gitano. Madrid: Unión musical española, n.d., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. C.R.7375.; Composer also known by the name: Bretón y Hernández, Tomás. (Box-folder 9/6)
      - La verbena de la paloma. Madrid: Dotésio, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 96 p.; Plate no. 7354 through 7366.; Contains printed publicity material for the publications of the Unión musical española, 8 p., in Spanish, dated 1916.; Language note: Spanish; Composer also known by the name: Bretón y Hernández, Tomás. (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Brown, Lew See: De Sylva, B. G.
    - Bull, John
      - Album of selected pieces. London: Novello, n.d., Solo piano; score; 36 p.; Plate no. 13451. (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Byrd, William
      - Three dances. London: Novello, n.d., Arranged by G. Bantock for solo piano; score; 12 p.; Plate no. 13263. (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Caplet, André
      - La cloche fêlée. Paris: Éditions de la nouvelle revue française, 1924., Voice and piano; score; 8 p.; Published as a supplement of La revue musicale, dated January 1924.; Language note: French (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Carpenter, John Alden
      - Krazy Kat. New York: G. Schirmer, 1922., Arranged by the composer for solo piano; score; 39 p.; Plate no. 30760c.; Includes printed cartoon illustrations of the title character by George Herriman. (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Chabrier, Emmanuel
      - Air de ballet. Paris: Costallat, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. C. & C.406. (Box-folder 9/12)
      - Bourrée fantasque. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Solo piano; score; 13 p.; Plate no. E.F. & C.1850. (Box-folder 9/13)
      - Briséïs. Paris: Enoch, 1897., Piano-vocal score; 126 p.; Plate no. E. & C.2006.; Language note: French (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Chabrier, Emmanuel and Maurice Le Boucher
      - Capriccio. Paris: Costallat, 1914., Solo piano; score; 20 p.; Plate no. 1949. (Box-folder 9/15)
      - Une education manquée. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 68 p.; Plate no. E.P. & F.407.; BOX: 10/2 Copy 2 of the above. Contains inlaid copyist's manuscript material; original unpublished recitatives (by Darius Milhaud?), 46 p.; contains extensive annotations in pencil and in ink.; Language note: French (Box-folder 10/1-2)
      - España. Paris: Enoch & Costallat, n.d., Full score; 61 p.; Plate no. E.F. & C.891. (Box-folder 10/3)
      - España. Paris: Enoch & Costallat, n.d., Arranged by the composer for two pianos; parts; 15 p.; 15 p.; Plate no. 893 (1), 893 (2). (Box-folder 10/4)
      - España. Paris: Enoch, 1911., Solo piano; score; 147 p.; Plate no. E. & C.7267. (Box-folder 10/5)
      - L'étoile. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 184 p.; Plate no. E.P. & F.258.; Contains annotations in pencil.; Language note: French (Box-folder 10/6)
      - Feuillet d'album. Paris: Enoch, 1897., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. E. & C.3298. (Box-folder 10/7)
      - Habañera. Paris: Enoch & Costallat, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. E.F. & C.1131.; 2 copies (Box-folder 10/8)
      - Impromptu. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Solo piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. E. & C.7941. (Box-folder 10/9)
      - L'invitation au voyage. Paris: Costallat, 1913., Voice and piano, with bassoon obbligato; piano score, bassoon part; 12 p.; 1 p.; Plate no. 1828.; Language note: French (Box-folder 10/10)
      - Joyeuse marche. Paris: Enoch & Costallat, n.d., Arranged by E. Alder for solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. E.F. & C.1731. (Box-folder 10/11)
      - Larghetto. Paris: Costallat, 1913., Arranged for horn or cello and piano; cello part, piano score; 3p.; 12 p.; Plate no. 1824. (Box-folder 10/12)
      - Pas redoublé. Paris: Costallat, 1913., Arranged by P. Lacome for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 1880. (Box-folder 10/13)
      - Pièces pittoresques. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Solo piano; score; 63 p.; Plate no. Litolff no. 1290.; Also published Brunswick: H. Litolff, n.d. (Box-folder 11/1)
      - [Dix] pièces pittoresques. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Solo piano; score; 60 p.; Plate no. E.F. & C. 2266, 2267, 2268, 2317, 1816, 2269, 2318, 2270, 2319, 6961. (Box-folder 11/2)
      - [Dix] pièces pittoresques: Menuet pompeux. Paris: Enoch & Costallat, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. E.F. & C.2319. (Box-folder 11/3)
      - Recueil de mélodies. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Voice/chorus and piano; score; 119 p.; Plate no. 5594 [-5595].; Language note: French (Box-folder 11/4)
      - Le roi malgré lui. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 423 p.; Plate no. E.F. & C.1348.; BOX: 11/6 Copy 2 of the above.; Language note: French (Box-folder 11/5-6)
      - Le roi malgré lui. [Paris]: Enoch & Costallat, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 142 p.; Plate no. A.C.738.; Contains annotations in pencil.; missing p. 1-18; Language note: French (Box-folder 12/1)
      - Ronde champêtre. Paris: Enoch, 1897., Solo piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. E. & C.3301. (Box-folder 12/2)
      - Ruy Blas. [Sérénade de Ruy Blas.] Paris: Costallat, 1913., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 1834.; Language note: French (Box-folder 12/3)
      - Souvenirs de Munich. Paris: Costallat, 1914., Piano, four hands; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 1948. (Box-folder 12/4)
      - Suite de valses. Paris: Costallat, 1913., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 1864. (Box-folder 12/5)
      - Tes yeux bleus. Paris: Costallat, 1913., Voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 1826.; Language note: French (Box-folder 12/6)
      - Trois valses romantiques. Paris: Enoch & Costallat, n.d., Two pianos; parts; 25 p.; 25 p.; Plate no. E.F. & C.401 (1), 401 (2), 402 (2), 403 (3). (Box-folder 12/7)
      - Trois valses romantiques. Paris: Enoch, n.d., Arranged by A. Cortot for piano, four hands; score; 47 p.; Plate no. E. & C.3958. (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Charpentier, Marc Antoine
      - Le malade imaginaire. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 48 p.; Plate no. D. & F.4723.; Language note: French (Box-folder 12/9)
    - Cherniavskiĭ, A.
      - Vial'tseva-Kontsert. St. Petersburg: I.G. TSimmerman, n.d., Solo piano; score; 13 p.; Plate no. Z.7294. (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Chopin, Frédéric
      - [Works.] [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., solo piano; score; [36] p.; incomplete fragments from what appears to be the same or similar edition(s); works include: op. 64, no. 1 (p. 31 through 38); op. 30, nos. 2-4; op. 33, no. 1 (p. 47 through 58); op. 33, no. 4 (p. 65 through 72); op. 63, nos. 1-3; op. 67, nos. 1-2 (p. 127 through 138) (Box-folder 12/11)
      - Études. Paris: A. Durand, 1915., Solo piano; score; 123 p.; Plate no. D. & F.9702. (Box-folder 12/12)
      - Mazurkas. Paris: A. Durand, 1915., Solo piano; score; 159 p.; Plate no. D. & F.9703.; BOX: 12/14 Copy 2 of the above; incomplete: p. 1-44, 77-124, 141-159 (end) only. (Box-folder 12/13-14)
      - Mazurke. [Composizioni, v. 3: Mazurke.] Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Solo piano; score; 239 p.; incomplete: p. 209 through 216 missing; Plate no. 104394. (Box-folder 13/1)
      - Mazurkas. [Klavierwerke, v. 6: Mazurkas.] See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68
      - Mazurkas. [Sämmtliche Pianoforte-Werke: Mazurkas.] Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Solo piano; score; 150 p.; Plate no. 6213. (Box-folder S/43)
      - Nocturnes. Paris: A. Durand, 1915., Solo piano; score; 100 p.; Plate no. D. & F.9704. (Box-folder 13/2)
      - Polonaises. Paris: A. Choudens, 1928., Solo piano; score; 94 p.; Plate no. A.C.12624 through 12634. (Box-folder 13/3)
      - Polonaise, op. 40, no. 1. Braunschweig: H. Litolff, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. Band 1046 No. 4. (Box-folder 13/4)
      - Préludes et rondos. Paris: A. Durand, 1915., Solo piano; score; 110 p.; Plate no. D. & F.9706. (Box-folder 13/5)
      - Valses. Paris: A. Durand, 1915., Solo piano; score; 77 p.; Plate no. D. & F.9709.; incomplete: missing p. 1-10, 27-28, 31-38, 41-48, 61-72 (ends at p. 77) (Box-folder 13/6)
      - Valse, op. 64, no. 2. Braunschweig: H. Litolff, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. Band 1044 No. 7. (Box-folder 13/7)
      - Waltzes. [Complete works for the pianoforte, v. 1: Waltzes.] New York: G. Schirmer, 1915., Solo piano; score; 76 p.; Plate no. 25502.; p. 51-54 missing (Box-folder 13/8)
      - Walzer. [Sämmtliche Pianoforte-Werke: Walzer.] Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Solo piano; score; 79 p.; Plate no. 8946.; Bound and filed with: Offenbach, Jacques.Les contes d'Hoffmann: selections. Arranged for solo piano; score. Moscow: A. Gutheil, n.d., 87 p. Plate no. A.7585 G. (Box-folder S/44)
    - Cimarosa, Domenico
      - Le astuzie femminili. Paris: L. Escudier, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 284 p.; Plate no. L.E.3332.; BOX: S/13 Copy 1 contains sparse annotations in pencil and inlaid manuscript material.; BOX: S/14 Copy 2 of the above; contains sparse annotations in pencil and inlaid manuscript material.; BOX: S/15 Copy 3 of the above; contains extensive annotations and inlaid manuscript material.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/13-15)
      - Le astuzie femminili. Milan: E. Sonzogno, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 164 p.; Plate no. E.S.14. (Box-folder 13/9)
      - Le astuzie femminili: Le ragazze che son di vent'anni (Act IV). Naples: T. Cottrau, n.d., Arranged for voice and piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 16284.; 2 copies; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 13/10)
      - Giannina e Bernardone. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 180 p.; Plate no. 42044.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/16)
      - Il matrimonio segreto. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 312 p.; Plate no. 41687.; BOX: 14/1 Copy 2 of the above.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder S/17, Box-folder 14/1)
      - Il matrimonio segreto. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 429 p.; Plate no. 29673 through 29694.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 14/2)
      - Il matrimonio segreto: Sinfonia. Milan: G. Ricordi, n.d., Arranged for small orchestra by L. Jacob; parts for: piano (condensed score) (13 p.); harmonium (10 p.); vn I (A), vn I (B), vn II (5 p. each); vla (4 p.); vc/cb (8 p.); fl, cl I, cl II, hn I, hn II, tpt, tbn (3 p. each); perc (1 p.).; Plate no. 110438. (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Cools, Eugène See: de Bozi, Harold and Cools, Eugène
    - Corelli, Arcangelo
      - Sonatas, op. 5. ["Opera quinta"] [S.l.]: [s.n.], n.d., Violin and continuo; score; 44 p.; Violin and continuo arranged on two staves. (Box-folder 15/1)
      - Sonate, op. 5, no. 6: 1. Grave, 2. Allegro. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 1 p.; 3 p.; Also published Paris: B. Roudanez, n.d.; Plate no. S.R. et Cie 71. (Box-folder 15/2)
      - Sonate, op. 5, no. 6: 3. Allegro, 4. Adagio, 5. Allegro. Paris: M. Senart, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part and piano score; 2 p.; 5 p.; Also published Paris: B. Roudanez, n.d.; Plate no. S.R. et Cie 72. (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Cottrau, T.
      - L'addio a Napoli See: I.B. Collections, Box 2 (S/63), p. 67-68
    - Couperin, François
      - Concert en sol majeur. [Les goûts réunis: Concert no. 8.] Paris: Éditions musicales transatlantiques, 1959., Arranged by F. Oubradous for orchestra; miniature score; 45 p.; Plate no. E.M.T. 522. (Box-folder 15/4)
      - Pièces de clavecin: v. 1. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo keyboard; score; 139 p.; Plate no. 6333.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 15/5)
      - Pièces de clavecin: v. 2. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo keyboard; score; 140 p.; Plate no. 6380. (Box-folder 15/6)
      - Pièces de clavecin: v. 3. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo keyboard; score; 115 p.; Plate no. 6457. (Box-folder 15/7)
      - Pièces de clavecin: v. 4. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo keyboard; score; 126 p.; Plate no. 6608. (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Crémieux, Octave
      - Kogda umiraet liubov'. Moscow: IU.G. TSimmerman, n.d., Voice and piano; vocal part and piano score; 1 p.; 2 p.; Plate no. Z.7058.; Language note: Russian; Language note: French (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Csenki, Imre
      - Gipsies. London: Hawkes, 1958., Full score; 77 p.; Plate no. B. & H.18321.; Contains photoreproduced typescript, 4 p., in French, of the ballet's synopsis. (Box-folder 15/10)
    - Cueva, Julio
      - Ajonjoli See: Oréfiche, Armando. Puchunguita
    - Cui, César
      - Feuille d'album See: I.B. Collections, Box 3 (S/64), p. 68-69
    - Dacquin, Louis Claude
      - [Deux pièces:] Rigaudon, Guitare. Paris: Costallat, n.d., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 8340.R. (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Darewski, Herman
      - Whispering. London: H. Darewski, 1920., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. H.D.M.P.Co.1004. (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Dargomyzhskiĭ, Aleksandr Sergeevich
      - Au bal. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', n.d., Voice and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 3835.; Language note: French (Box-folder 16/3)
      - Baba IAga. St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, n.d., Arranged by the composer for two pianos; score; 25 p.; Plate no. 251. (Box-folder 16/4)
      - Bez uma, bez razuma. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', 1885., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. K.2097 G.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 16/5)
      - Bezumno zhazhdat' tvoeĭ vstriechi. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Two voices and piano; score; 2 p.; Plate no. 13.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 16/6)
      - Charuĭ menia, charuĭ! Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 10361.; Language note: Russian; Language note: German (Box-folder 16/7)
      - Chukhonskaia fantaziia. [=Fantaisie sur des airs finlandais.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, n.d., Full score; 45 p.; Plate no. 247. (Box-folder 16/8)
      - Chukhonskaia fantaziia. [=Fantaisie finoise.] St. Petersburg: W. Bessel, n.d., Orchestral parts for: vn I (7 p.) [9 copies]; vn II, vla (6 p. each); vc/cb (11 p.); fl I, fl II/picc, ob I, ob II, cl I, cl II, bn I, bn II (4 p. each); hn I, hn II, hn III, hn IV, tpt I, tpt II, tenor tbn, bass tbn, ophicleide, timp (3 p. each); pc (2 p.).; Plate no. 252 (a) through 252 (w). (Box-folder 16/9)
      - Dievitsy krasavitsy. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Two voices and piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 10327.; Language note: Russian; Language note: German (Box-folder 16/10)
      - Dushechka dievitsa. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 10331.; Language note: Russian; Language note: German (Box-folder 16/11)
      - IA pomniu, gluboko. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.5848 G.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 16/12)
      - IA vse eshchë ego liubliu! Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', 1888., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. K.2096 G.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 16/13)
      - IA zatepliu sviechu. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', 1899., Voice and piano; score; 2 p.; Plate no. A.7784 G.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 16/14)
      - Jamais! Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', 1885., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 2408.; Language note: French (Box-folder 16/15)
      - Kamen' tiazhelyĭ na serdtsie lezhit. Moscow: Gosudarstvennoe izdatel'stvo, Muzykal'nyĭ sektor, 1923., Two voices and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. (3728) 10292.; Language note: Russian; Published in Moscow and Petrograd. (Box-folder 16/16)
      - Kamennyĭ gost'. [=The stone guest.] St. Petersburg: V. Bessel', 1872., Piano-vocal score; 126 p.; Plate no. 153.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 16/17)
      - Likhoradushka. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', 1885., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. K.2098 G.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 16/18)
      - Liubila, liubliu ia, viek budu liubit'. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', 1892., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.6300 G.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 16/19)
      - Malorossiĭskiĭ kozachëk. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Arranged by the composer for piano, four hands; score; 15 p.; Plate no. 333. (Box-folder 16/20)
      - Mel'nik. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', 1897., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. K.2100 G.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 16/21)
      - Mne grustno. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 10324.; Language note: Russian; Language note: German (Box-folder 16/22)